<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tooltips>
<tooltip>
  <name>algorithm</name>
  <text>
Determines which program will be used to layout your drawing.
Select an algorithm to see a sample layout.
</text>
</tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>dot</name>
    <text>
The DOT algorithm is used for hierarchical diagrams, such as
organisation charts and flowcharts, where some shapes have
more importance (or come before) others.

If arrows would make sense in your diagram (even if they are not drawn),
then DOT is the appropriate algorithm.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  
  <tooltip>
    <name>neato</name>
    <text>
      The NEATO algorithm is used for diagrams with no
      hierarchy, such as network, database and software
      engineering diagrams.
    </text>
  </tooltip>

  <tooltip>
    <name>fdp</name>
    <text>
      The FDP algorithm is similar to NEATO, but it supports subgraphs.
      Each subgraph is a Visio layer, which is layed out seperately
      and then the subgraphs are layed out as blocks to create
      the complete diagram.
    </text>
  </tooltip>

  <tooltip>
    <name>twopi</name>
    <text>
      The TWOPI algorithm lays out shapes in concentric circles around
      a root node (which you must define). This alogorithm is suitable for
      complex network diagrams.
    </text>
  </tooltip>

  <tooltip>
    <name>circo</name>
    <text>
      The CIRCO algorithm lays out shapes initially on a circle, whilst 
      minimising edge crossings. This algorithm is suitable for
      simple network diagrams.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
<tooltip>
  <name>rankdir</name>
  <text>
    Determines whether your diagram will be layed out top-to-bottom or 
    left-to-right. This only has meaning for hierarchical diagrams, typically
    those laid out with the DOT alogorithm.
  </text>
</tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>TB</name>
    <text>
    Lays out the diagram top-to-bottom with the head node at the top.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>LR</name>
    <text>
      Lays out the diagram left-to-right with the head node on the left.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>leafstack</name>
    <text>
    When laying out a hierarchical diagram from top-to-bottom, this option
    causes the lowest nodes (the leaves) to be stacked vertically underneath their parent rather 
    than side-by-side. 
    
    This is useful for tree-style diagrams, which often become wide and short; stacking the
    leaves makes the diagram narrower and taller, more suitable for portrait display.
    
    'ALL' stacks the bottom-most leaves at all levels. 
    'LOWEST' only stacks leaves at the lowest level.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>aspectratio</name>
    <text>
      Sets the height-width ratio of the diagram.
      For ISO 216 "A" paper sizes, use 0.707 for landscape and 1.414 for portrait.
      Set the aspect ratio to zero to allow the diagram to size automatically.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>btnLayout</name>
    <text>
    Layout the current diagram using the current settings.
    Tip: You can use 'undo' (Ctrl-Z) to revert to the previous layout
    (layout is considered as a single operation).
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>btnImportDOT</name>
    <text>
    Import a DOT file as a new Visio page. The format of DOT files is
    described at www.graphviz.org.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>setroot</name>
    <text>
    When using the TWOPI algorithm, you must define the root node (the shape which is the logical
    'centre' of the diagram). To set the root node, select the root shape and click 'Set Root'.
    You only need to do this once, it is saved with the Visio diagram.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>showroot</name>
    <text>
    Selects the current root node.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapeis</name>
    <text>
    By default, GraphVizio performs layout by moving existing shapes. This option allows you to replace existing shapes with 
    a new shape during layout, for example to apply a consistent style. 
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapename</name>
    <text>
    Specifies which shape will be used to replace existing shapes during layout. The available shapes shown are those in
    in the GraphVizio stencil, GraphVizio.VSS. You can edit and add to this stencil with Graph->Tools->Stencil.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapefillcolours</name>
    <text>
    When using a shape from the GraphVizio stencil, 
    this option allows you to select a specific fill colour.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapefillcolour</name>
    <text>
    Click to select a fill colour for shapes.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapetextcolours</name>
    <text>
      When using a shape from the GraphVizio stencil, 
      this option allows you to select a specific text colour.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapetextcolour</name>
    <text>
      Click to select a text colour for shapes.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapelinecolours</name>
    <text>
    This option allows you to specify which colour will be used to draw lines (connectors).
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>shapelinecolour</name>
    <text>
      Click to select a colour to draw lines (connectors).
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>connectorstyle</name>
    <text>
    By default, lines (connectors) are drawn using the style of the chosen GraphViz alorithm.
    This option allows you to use a different line style, without affecting the layout.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>straight</name>
    <text>      
    Forces connectors to be drawn as straight lines, which may pass behind shapes.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>splines</name>
    <text>
    Uses curved lines to draw connectors. Selecting this option doesn't mean that all connectors will
    necessarily be curved, the result depends on the GraphViz algorithm being used.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>connectorname</name>
    <text>
      Use a specific connector to draw lines. The available connectors shown are those in
      in the GraphVizio stencil, GraphVizio.VSS. You can edit and add to this stencil with Graph->Tools->Stencil.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>connectto</name>
    <text>
    By default, GraphVizio connects shapes by creating connection points determined by the GraphViz alogorithm.
    You can override this behaviour, to force connections to the top, bottom, nearest quadrant etc.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>ideal</name>
    <text>
      Connections are made at the 'ideal' point on the periphery of the shape. This is the default.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>topbottom</name>
    <text>
    Forces connectors to be attached to the top/bottom of shapes, in the middle.
    This typically used in conjunction with a dynamic connector to draw organisation charts.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>quadrant</name>
    <text>
    Forces connectors to be attached in the middle of the top, right, bottom or left of the shape.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>strict</name>
    <text>
      Determines if the diagram should be layed-out using the 'strict' option, which forbids self-arcs
      and multi-edges. This is documented at http://www.graphviz.org/Documentation/dotguide.pdf.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>overlap</name>
    <text>
      Determines how GraphViz will resolve overlapping shapes. This has considerable influence on the results
      and is the first option you should experiment with. The possible values are described at
      http://www.graphviz.org/doc/info/attrs.html#d:overlap
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>drawboundingboxes</name>
    <text>
    When checked, draws a black box around each graph and sub-graph during layout.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>type</name>
    <text>
    Sets the type of diagram to be drawn. In a nutshell, Directed graphs are those which would logically be drawn 
    with arrows (representing flow or hierarchy) whilst Undirected graphs are drawn without directional relations.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>digraph</name>
    <text>
    Draws a directed graph (which would logically be drawn
      with arrows representing flow or hierarchy).
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>graph</name>
    <text>
    Draws an undirected graph (a diagram without directional relations).
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>rankbyposition</name>
    <text>
    Reverse the direction of connectors so as to make shapes nearer the top and left of the page
    point to those further down and on the right. 
    This allows you to make a shape the 'root' shape at the top simply by dragging it above
    all the other shapes performing the layout.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>seed</name>
    <text>
      Determines the initial placement of shapes on the page.
      By default, this number is incremented every time you layout a graph, creating a 
      unique layout every time. If you find a particular layout pleasing, set the "lock seed" flag,
      so that the same positioning will be used for every future layout.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
  <tooltip>
    <name>lockseed</name>
    <text>
      Locks the seed value, to produce a repeatable layout.
    </text>
  </tooltip>
</tooltips>